<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on gRPC</title>
    <link>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on gRPC</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dear gRPC</title>
      <link>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/hello-pancakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/hello-pancakes/</guid>
      <description>Dear gRPC,
We messed up. We are so sorry that we missed your birthday this year. Last year we celebrated with cake and fanfare, but this year we dropped the ball. Please don&amp;rsquo;t think that we love you any less.
You&amp;rsquo;re 4 now and that&amp;rsquo;s a big milestone! You&amp;rsquo;re part of so much amazing technology at companies like Salesforce, Netflix, Spotify, Fanatics, and of course, Google. In fact just this week the biggest API Google has went production-ready with gRPC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The state of gRPC in the browser</title>
      <link>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/state-of-grpc-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/state-of-grpc-web/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a guest post by&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jbrandhorst.com&#34;&gt;Johan Brandhorst&lt;/a&gt;, Software Engineer at&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.infosum.com&#34;&gt;InfoSum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;gRPC 1.0 was released in August 2016 and has since grown to become one of the
premier technical solutions for application communications. It has been adopted
by startups, enterprise companies, and open source projects worldwide.
Its support for polyglot environments, focus on performance, type safety, and
developer productivity has transformed the way developers design their
architectures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far the benefits have largely only been available to mobile
app and backend developers, whilst frontend developers have had to continue to
rely on JSON REST interfaces as their primary means of information exchange.
However, with the release of gRPC-Web, gRPC is poised to become a valuable
addition in the toolbox of frontend developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll describe some of the history of gRPC in the browser, explore
the state of the world today, and share some thoughts on the future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gRPC Meets .NET SDK And Visual Studio: Automatic Codegen On Build</title>
      <link>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/grpc-dotnet-build/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/grpc-dotnet-build/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As part of Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s move towards its cross-platform .NET offering, they have
greatly simplified the project file format, and allowed a tight integration of
third-party code generators with .NET projects. We are listening, and now proud
to introduce integrated compilation of Protocol Buffer and gRPC service
&lt;code&gt;.proto&lt;/code&gt; files in .NET C# projects starting with the version 1.17 of the
Grpc.Tools NuGet package, now available from Nuget.org.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You no longer need to use hand-written scripts to generate code from &lt;code&gt;.proto&lt;/code&gt;
files: The .NET build magic handles this for you. The integrated tools locate
the proto compiler and gRPC plugin, standard Protocol Buffer imports, and track
dependencies before invoking the code generators, so that the generated C#
source files are never out of date, at the same time keeping regeneration to
the minimum required. In essence, &lt;code&gt;.proto&lt;/code&gt; files are treated as first-class
sources in a .NET C# project.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing gRPC Language Stacks</title>
      <link>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/grpc-stacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/grpc-stacks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is a high level overview of the gRPC Stacks.  Each of the &lt;strong&gt;10&lt;/strong&gt; default languages supported by gRPC has multiple layers, allowing you to customize what pieces you want in your application.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gRPC-Web is Generally Available</title>
      <link>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/grpc-web-ga/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/grpc-web-ga/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are excited to announce the GA release of
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.npmjs.com/package/grpc-web&#34;&gt;gRPC-Web&lt;/a&gt;, a JavaScript client library
that enables web apps to communicate directly with gRPC backend services,
without requiring an HTTP server to act as an intermediary. &amp;ldquo;GA&amp;rdquo; means that
gRPC-Web is now Generally Available and stable and qualified for production use.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A short introduction to Channelz</title>
      <link>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/a_short_introduction_to_channelz/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/a_short_introduction_to_channelz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Channelz is a tool that provides comprehensive runtime info about connections at
different levels in gRPC. It is designed to help debug live programs, which may
be suffering from network, performance, configuration issues, etc. The
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/grpc/proposal/blob/master/A14-channelz.md&#34;&gt;gRFC&lt;/a&gt; provides a
detailed explanation of channelz design and is the canonical reference for all
channelz implementations across languages. The purpose of this blog is to
familiarize readers with channelz service and how to use it for debugging
issues. The context of this post is set in
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/grpc/grpc-go&#34;&gt;gRPC-Go&lt;/a&gt;, but the overall idea should be
applicable across languages. At the time of writing, channelz is available for
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/grpc/grpc-go&#34;&gt;gRPC-Go&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/grpc/grpc-java&#34;&gt;gRPC-Java&lt;/a&gt;. Support for
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/grpc/grpc&#34;&gt;C++&lt;/a&gt; and wrapped languages is coming soon.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gRPC on HTTP/2 Engineering a Robust, High Performance Protocol</title>
      <link>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/grpc_on_http2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/grpc_on_http2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href=&#34;https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/http2_smarter_at_scale&#34;&gt;previous article&lt;/a&gt;, we explored how HTTP/2 dramatically increases network efficiency and enables real-time communication by providing a framework for long-lived connections. In this article, we’ll look at how gRPC builds on HTTP/2’s long-lived connections to create a performant, robust platform for inter-service communication. We will explore the relationship between gRPC and HTTP/2, how gRPC manages HTTP/2 connections, and how gRPC uses HTTP/2 to keep connections alive, healthy, and utilized.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gRPC &#43; JSON</title>
      <link>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/grpc-with-json/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/grpc-with-json/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So you&amp;rsquo;ve bought into this whole RPC thing and want to try it out, but aren&amp;rsquo;t quite sure about Protocol Buffers.  Your existing code encodes your own objects, or perhaps you have code that needs a particular encoding.  What to do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, gRPC is encoding agnostic!  You can still get a lot of the benefits of gRPC without using Protobuf.  In this post we&amp;rsquo;ll go through how to make gRPC work with other encodings and types.  Let&amp;rsquo;s try using JSON.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take the gRPC Survey!</title>
      <link>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/take-the-grpc-survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/take-the-grpc-survey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-grpc-project-wants-your-feedback&#34;&gt;The gRPC Project wants your feedback!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gRPC project is looking for feedback to improve the gRPC experience. To do this, we are running a &lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/gRPC18survey&#34;&gt;gRPC user survey&lt;/a&gt;. We invite you to participate  and provide input that will help us better plan and prioritize.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTTP/2 Smarter At Scale</title>
      <link>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/http2_smarter_at_scale/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/http2_smarter_at_scale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Much of the web today runs on HTTP/1.1. The spec for HTTP/1.1 was published in June of 1999, just shy of 20 years ago. A lot has changed since then, which makes it all the more remarkable that HTTP/1.1 has persisted and flourished for so long. But in some areas it’s beginning to show its age; for the most part, in that the designers weren’t building for the scale at which HTTP/1.1 would be used and the astonishing amount of traffic that it would come to handle. A not-so-bad case is that subsequent tests can&amp;rsquo;t pass because of a leaked resource from the previous test. The worst case is that some subsequent tests pass that wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have passed at all if the previously passed test had not leaked a resource.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gracefully clean up in gRPC JUnit tests</title>
      <link>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/gracefully_clean_up_in_grpc_junit_tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/gracefully_clean_up_in_grpc_junit_tests/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is best practice to always clean up gRPC resources such as client channels, servers, and previously attached Contexts whenever they are no longer needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is even true for JUnit tests, because otherwise leaked resources may not only linger in your machine forever, but also interfere with subsequent tests. A not-so-bad case is that subsequent tests can&amp;rsquo;t pass because of a leaked resource from the previous test. The worst case is that some subsequent tests pass that wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have passed at all if the previously passed test had not leaked a resource.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gRPC ❤ Kotlin</title>
      <link>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/kotlin-gradle-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/kotlin-gradle-projects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Did you know that gRPC Java now has out of box support for Kotlin projects built with Gradle? &lt;a href=&#34;https://kotlinlang.org/&#34;&gt;Kotlin&lt;/a&gt; is a modern, statically typed language developed by JetBrains that targets the JVM and Android. It is generally easy for Kotlin programs to interoperate with existing Java libraries. To improve this experience further, we have added support to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/google/protobuf-gradle-plugin/releases&#34;&gt;protobuf-gradle-plugin&lt;/a&gt; so that the generated Java libraries are automatically picked up by Kotlin. You can now add the protobuf-gradle-plugin to your Kotlin project, and use gRPC just like you would with a typical Java project.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So You Want to Optimize gRPC - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/optimizing-grpc-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/optimizing-grpc-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How fast is gRPC?  Pretty fast if you understand how modern clients and servers are built.  In
&lt;a href=&#34;https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/optimizing-grpc-part-1&#34;&gt;part 1&lt;/a&gt;, I showed how to get an easy &lt;strong&gt;60%&lt;/strong&gt; improvement.  In this
post I show how to get a &lt;strong&gt;10000%&lt;/strong&gt; improvement.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So You Want to Optimize gRPC - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/optimizing-grpc-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/optimizing-grpc-part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A common question with gRPC is how to make it fast.  The gRPC library offers users access to high
performance RPCs, but it isn&amp;rsquo;t always clear how to achieve this.  Because this question is common
enough I thought I would try to show my thought process when tuning programs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gRPC and Deadlines</title>
      <link>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/deadlines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/deadlines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR Always set a deadline&lt;/strong&gt;. This post explains why we recommend being deliberate about setting deadlines, with useful code snippets to show you how.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018-01-19 gRPC-Go Engineering Practices</title>
      <link>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/2018-01-22-grpc-go-engineering-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/2018-01-22-grpc-go-engineering-practices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the start of the new year, and almost the end of my first full year on the
gRPC-Go project, so I&amp;rsquo;d like to take this opportunity to provide an update on
the state of gRPC-Go development and give some visibility into how we manage the
project.  For me, personally, this is the first open source project to which
I&amp;rsquo;ve meaningfully contributed, so this year has been a learning experience for
me.  Over this year, the team has made constant improvements to our work habits
and communication.  I still see room for improvement, but I believe we are in a
considerably better place than we were a year ago.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The gRPC Meetup Kit</title>
      <link>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/meetup-kit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/meetup-kit/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;If you have ever wanted to run an event around &lt;a href=&#34;http://grpc.io&#34;&gt;gRPC&lt;/a&gt;, but didn&amp;rsquo;t know where to start, or wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure what content is available - we have released the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/grpc-ecosystem/meetup-kit&#34;&gt;gRPC Meetup Kit&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2017-08-22 gRPC-Go performance Improvements</title>
      <link>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/2017-08-22-grpc-go-perf-improvements/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/2017-08-22-grpc-go-perf-improvements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;margin-bottom:5%&#34;&gt;For past few months we&amp;rsquo;ve been working on improving gRPC-Go performance. This includes improving network utilization, optimizing CPU usage and memory allocations. Most of our recent effort has been focused around revamping gRPC-Go flow control. After several optimizations and new features we&amp;rsquo;ve been able to improve quite significantly, especially on high-latency networks. We expect users that are working with high-latency networks and large messages to see an order of magnitude performance gain.
Benchmark results at the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog summarizes the work we have done so far (in chronological order) to improve performance and lays out our near-future plans.&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2017-08-17 Community Meeting Update</title>
      <link>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/2017-08-17-community-meeting-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/2017-08-17-community-meeting-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Next Community Meeting:&lt;/strong&gt; Thursday, August 31, 2017 11am Pacific Time (US and Canada)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing out of the box support for gRPC in the Flatbuffers serialization library.</title>
      <link>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/flatbuffers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/flatbuffers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The recent release of Flatbuffers &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/google/flatbuffers/releases&#34;&gt;version 1.7&lt;/a&gt; introduced truly zero-copy support for gRPC out of the box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://google.github.io/flatbuffers/&#34;&gt;Flatbuffers&lt;/a&gt; is a serialization library that allows you to access serialized data without first unpacking it or allocating any
additional data structures. It was originally designed for games and other resource constrained applications, but is now finding more general use, both by teams within Google and in other companies such as Netflix and Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gRPC Load Balancing</title>
      <link>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/loadbalancing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/loadbalancing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post describes various load balancing scenarios seen when deploying gRPC. If you use &lt;a href=&#34;https://cjyabraham.github.io/&#34;&gt;gRPC&lt;/a&gt; with multiple backends, this document is for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A large scale gRPC deployment typically has a number of identical back-end instances, and a number of clients. Each server has a certain capacity. Load balancing is used for distributing the load from clients optimally across available servers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gRPC in Helm</title>
      <link>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/helmgrpc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/helmgrpc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our guest post today comes from Brian Hardock, a software engineer from Deis working on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://helm.sh/&#34;&gt;Helm&lt;/a&gt; project.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Helm is the package manager for Kubernetes. Helm provides its users with a customizable mechanism for
managing distributed applications and controlling their deployment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have the good fortune to be a member of the phenomenal open-source Kubernetes Helm community serving as
a core contributor. My first day working with the Helm team was spent prototyping the architecture for
the next generation of Helm. By the end of that day, we had procured the preliminary RPC protocol data model
used to enable communication between Helm and its in-cluster server component, Tiller.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migration to Google Cloud Platform — gRPC &amp; grpc-gateway</title>
      <link>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/yygrpc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/yygrpc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our guest post today comes from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/miguel-mendez-008231/&#34;&gt;Miguel Mendez&lt;/a&gt; of Yik Yak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was originally a part of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/yik-yak-eng&#34;&gt;Yik Yak Engineering Blog&lt;/a&gt; which focused on sharing the lessons learned as we evolved Yik Yak from early-stage startup code running in Amazon Web Services to an eventual incremental rewrite, re-architecture, and live-migration to Google Cloud Platform.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our previous blog &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/yik-yak-eng/migration-to-google-cloud-platform-overview-9b5e5c17c368&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; we gave an overview of our migration to Google Cloud Platform from Amazon Web Services. In this post we will drill down into the role that &lt;a href=&#34;https://cjyabraham.github.io/&#34;&gt;gRPC&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/grpc-ecosystem/grpc-gateway&#34;&gt;grpc-gateway&lt;/a&gt; played in that migration and share some lessons which we picked up along the way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building gRPC services with bazel and rules_protobuf</title>
      <link>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/bazel_rules_protobuf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/bazel_rules_protobuf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cjyabraham.github.io/&#34;&gt;gRPC&lt;/a&gt; makes it easier to build high-performance
microservices by providing generated service entrypoints in a variety
of different languages.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://bazel.io&#34;&gt;Bazel&lt;/a&gt; complements these
efforts with a capable and fast polyglot build environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/pubref/rules_protobuf&#34;&gt;rules_protobuf&lt;/a&gt; extends
bazel and makes it easier develop gRPC services.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gRPC at VSCO</title>
      <link>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/vscogrpc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/vscogrpc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our guest post today comes from Robert Sayre and Melinda Lu of VSCO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2011, &lt;a href=&#34;https://vsco.co&#34;&gt;VSCO&lt;/a&gt; is a community for expression—empowering people to create, discover and connect through images and words. VSCO is in the process of migrating their stack to gRPC.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why we have decided to move our APIs to gRPC</title>
      <link>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/vendastagrpc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/vendastagrpc/</guid>
      <description>Our guest post today comes from Dale Hopkins, CTO of Vendasta.
Vendasta started out 8 years ago as a point solution provider of products for small business. From the beginning we partnered with media companies and agencies who have armies of salespeople and existing relationships with those businesses to sell our software. It is estimated that over 30 million small businesses exist in the United States alone, so scalability of our SaaS solution was considered one of our top concerns from the beginning and it was the reason we started with Google App Engine and Datastore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gRPC Project is now 1.0 and ready for production deployments</title>
      <link>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/gablogpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/gablogpost/</guid>
      <description>Today, the gRPC project has reached a significant milestone with its 1.0 release. Languages moving to 1.0 include C++, Java, Go, Node, Ruby, Python and C# across Linux, Windows, and Mac. Objective-C and Android Java support on iOS and Android is also moving to 1.0. The 1.0 release means that the core protocol and API surface are now stable with measured performance, stress tested and developers can rely on these APIs and deploy in production, they will follow semantic versioning from here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gRPC with REST and Open APIs</title>
      <link>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/coreos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/coreos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our guest post today comes from Brandon Phillips of &lt;a href=&#34;https://coreos.com/&#34;&gt;CoreOS&lt;/a&gt;. CoreOS builds open source projects and products for Linux Containers. Their flagship product for consensus and discovery &lt;a href=&#34;https://coreos.com/etcd/&#34;&gt;etcd&lt;/a&gt; and their container engine &lt;a href=&#34;https://coreos.com/rkt/&#34;&gt;rkt&lt;/a&gt; are early adopters of gRPC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the key reasons CoreOS chose gRPC is because it uses HTTP/2, enabling applications to present both a HTTP 1.1 REST/JSON API and an efficient gRPC interface on a single TCP port (available for Go). This provides developers with compatibility with the REST web ecosystem, while advancing a new, high-efficiency RPC protocol. With the recent release of Go 1.6, Go ships with a stable &lt;code&gt;net/http2&lt;/code&gt; package by default.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gRPC - now with easy installation.</title>
      <link>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/installation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today we are happy to provide an update that significantly simplifies the getting started experience for gRPC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;For most languages, &lt;strong&gt;the gRPC runtime can now be installed in a single step via native package managers&lt;/strong&gt; such as &lt;code&gt;npm&lt;/code&gt; for Node.js, &lt;code&gt;gem&lt;/code&gt; for Ruby and &lt;code&gt;pip&lt;/code&gt; for Python. Even though our Node, Ruby and Python runtimes are wrapped on gRPC&amp;rsquo;s C core, users now don&amp;rsquo;t need to explicitly pre-install the C core library as a package in most Linux distributions. We autofetch it for you :-).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For Java, we have simplified the steps needed to add gRPC support to your build tools&lt;/strong&gt; by providing plugins for Maven and Gradle. These let you easily depend on the core runtime to deploy or ship generated libraries into production environments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can also use our Dockerfiles to use these updated packages - deploying microservices built on gRPC should now be a very simple experience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Cloud PubSub - with the power of gRPC!</title>
      <link>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/pubsub/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/pubsub/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cloud.google.com/pubsub/&#34;&gt;Google Cloud PubSub&lt;/a&gt; is Google&amp;rsquo;s scalable real-time messaging service that lets users send and receive messages between independent applications. It&amp;rsquo;s an important part of Google Cloud Platform&amp;rsquo;s big data offering, and is used by customers worldwide to build their own robust, global services. However, until now, the only way to use the Cloud PubSub API was via JSON over HTTP. That&amp;rsquo;s all changed with the release of &lt;a href=&#34;https://cloud.google.com/blog/big-data/2016/03/announcing-grpc-alpha-for-google-cloud-pubsub&#34;&gt;PubSub gRPC alpha&lt;/a&gt;. Now &lt;strong&gt;users can access PubSub via gRPC&lt;/strong&gt; and benefit from all the advantages it brings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gRPC releases Beta, opening door for use in production environments.</title>
      <link>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/beta_release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/beta_release/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;
    The gRPC team is excited to announce the immediate availability of gRPC Beta. This release marks an important point in API stability and going forward most API changes are expected to be additive in nature. This milestone opens the door for gRPC use in production environments.
&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gRPC Motivation and Design Principles.</title>
      <link>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cjyabraham.github.io/blog/principles/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;h2&gt;Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google has been using a single general-purpose RPC infrastructure called Stubby to connect the large number of microservices running within and across our data centers for over a decade. Our internal systems have long embraced the microservice architecture gaining popularity today. Having a uniform, cross-platform RPC infrastructure has allowed for the rollout of fleet-wide improvements in efficiency, security, reliability and behavioral analysis critical to supporting the incredible growth seen in that period.
&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>